[
    {
        "question": "Man made ............... are an important and effective means of communication",
        "options": [
            "Mobiles",
            "Technology",
            "Laptops",
            "Satellites"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Transport facilities can develop well in the ...............",
        "options": [
            "Plains",
            "Hills",
            "Valley",
            "Plateaus"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The western part of the Satara district is occupied by the Sahyadris and its offshoot and its elevation is ...............",
        "options": [
            "Higher",
            "Shorter",
            "Lower",
            "Taller"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Many ............... are happening through internet",
        "options": [
            "Robberies",
            "Murders",
            "Crimes",
            "Fights"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Bridges and tunnels connect the Multilane National ..............",
        "options": [
            "Highways",
            "Railways",
            "Airways",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the construction and maintenance of the National Highways?",
        "options": [
            "State Government",
            "Central Government",
            "Federal Government",
            "National Government"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Development of ............... infrastructure is an indicator of the development of the country or that region.",
        "options": [
            "Carriage",
            "Deportation",
            "Transportation",
            "Distribution"
        ],
        "answer": 3
      },
    {
        "question": "While reading a ..............., we can easily see the patterns of transport route.",
        "options": [
            "Book",
            "Newspaper",
            "Blog",
            "Map"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "............... transport is carried out on a large scale on national highway.",
        "options": [
            "Shipment",
            "Consignment",
            "Freight",
            "Shipping"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "For this organ transfer, all types of routes are cleared of all obstacles. This is called .............",
        "options": [
            "Black Corridor",
            "Green Corridor",
            "Blue Corridor",
            "Red Corridor"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Pipelines are used to carry ...............",
        "options": [
            "Coal",
            "Oil",
            "Wood",
            "None"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Way of moving goods and people from one place to other place is called ............",
        "options": [
            "Management",
            "Organization",
            "Pollution",
            "Transportation"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "satellite images obtained by remote sensing facilitates the study of ...............",
        "options": [
            "Resources",
            "Forests",
            "Minerals",
            "Water"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Process of receiving and transmitting of messages, ideas and information is called ...............",
        "options": [
            "Communication",
            "Narration",
            "Predation",
            "Summation"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Name one Mass Media communication.",
        "options": [
            "Television",
            "Mobiles",
            "Satellite",
            "Apps"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Through ............... we can talk to many people at a time",
        "options": [
            "Video-shooting",
            "Video-conferencing",
            "Video-graphy",
            "Video-gaming"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the biggest port in the country?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Tuticorin",
            "Kochi",
            "Kandla"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Fastest wide spread mode of communication.",
        "options": [
            "Radio",
            "Internet",
            "T.V",
            "Mobiles, Newspapers"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "There are roadways, railways, waterways, airways and pipelines by which ............... can be done.",
        "options": [
            "Carriage",
            "Transportation",
            "Deportation",
            "Distribution"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The freight transport by trucks is ............... then railways.",
        "options": [
            "Cheaper",
            "Faster",
            "Reasonable",
            "Costlier"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Area of high relief have limited transport facilities.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "............... growth gets a boost with well developed transport system.",
        "options": [
            "Industrial",
            "Agricultural",
            "Economic",
            "Transportation"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "There is a correlation between transport routes and ............... of a region.",
        "options": [
            "Climate",
            "Physiography",
            "Population",
            "Rainfall"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Train that carry as much as 600 trucks is called ...............",
        "options": [
            "Luxury train",
            "Bullet train",
            "Freight train",
            "Double-stack unit train"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Means that helps people to travel from one place to another are called .............. .",
        "options": [
            "Mode of protocol",
            "Mode of organization",
            "Mode of management",
            "Mode of transport"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    }
]